personally I think that uh the best use of of AI is really like a like a pair like someone you're pair programming with and not someone as not not not a tool to just replace the act of writing code or worse outsourcing your thinking.
And I think there's a tendency like you know because AI is so exciting, you want to put AI everywhere and be seen as someone who's very you know um what do you call it? like on the ball I guess with with AI, uh that you feel this pressure of like you know I just got to I got to increase my productivity. I got to ship like 100 PRs this week and barely understand what I'm doing and you know vibe code my way to a million PR or whatever.
Um, but I think, you know, um, one of the things that I've personally seen is that although when I use AI, I save some time, you know, writing the code, I actually find myself spending more time reviewing what the AI did and like correcting it.
So, you know, like I've I've tried the the thing that a lot of people say, like, you know, you uh instead of prompting an AI to just build the feature outright, you sort of get it to uh build a spec for you first, then you review that spec and then you do that whole thing then it's like Okay, so I assume you can see my screen. Yes, yeah, we're good. So, yeah, today, yeah, I think I think the big theme for me as I've been using agents to write code, and I'm sure a lot of you have had the same experience as well, is how do you trust it?
You know, especially if you are an engineer that's been writing code for a very long time, you have a lot of opinions and lessons that you've learned about doing good engineering. And when you see agents just, you know, winging it and you know, guessing, hallucinating, uh, you know, confidently stating that they found the smoking gun uh for the hundredth time, uh, but it's actually not the real problem, you lose a lot of trust.
And when you lose when you don't have much trust in your agents, I feel like you you really can't get the most out of them.
And for me, the parallel is like with management. Uh, so if I'm a manager, an engineering manager of a team and I have a bunch of, you know, I have a team of engineers uh on my team and I don't trust them, then the motor of operation I'm going to be in is going to be like micromanagement, right? I'll have to spend a lot of time looking over my reports shoulders and checking that they're doing their work well, you know, that they're not shipping bugs to production.
And so I drew this chart because uh it's not it's not a very scientific chart, but like this is how I imagine myself and my journey through using agents.
So, you know, like fast forward or back forward uh or fast back, uh fast backwards like a year or so, when you know, nobody was or not many people were using agents to code, uh I think you uh you get into this mode where you are in very heavily in the loop with one or several like a handful of agents, and you find yourself just constantly figure, you know, trying to understand what your agents are doing uh and you're very, very in-loop.
You're watching every single output. You are sitting there prompting, um, and you really can't parallelize beyond that because you don't again, you don't have that trust, right?
You can't go to 100 agents, uh spawn 100 agents when you don't even trust the output of one agent. So, over the past 5 months, I feel like I've really been able to uh like ascend this trust curve, and now I'm at the point where uh I actually have, it sounds kind of scary to say this, and it makes me sound like a slopfire this, but I promise I'm not.
But I actually have my agents now um auto merging PRs for me, uh which is like a wild thing to say, but um like I woke up today and there were like 20 PRs landed, and I just reviewed them on main, like they were already landed, and they were good.
Uh, so how did I get to that point is basically what I wanted to talk about today. Uh, and again, like yeah, feel free to jump in if you have questions, Colin.
Um, but uh oh yeah, of course I got to show this this chart, uh, where uh, you know, do not trust someone requested to control my computer, uh, probably won't do that. Uh, but, yeah, so this chart, I think I I'm sharing the chart not to kind of like flex, but to kind of show like the journey.
Like, so you can see like the curve, like it sort of like inversely matches the contributions I've been able to land at cursor.
So, I joined 5 months ago, and 5 months ago like I, you know, my first month I was like not very productive because I was obvi, you know, I was learning the code base, didn't know what the heck was going on. And as I got more confident in in my agents, uh, I've really been able to kind of ramp up my productivity. Uh, and again, like yeah, like last month I shipped 1,000 PRs, which is ridiculous.
you're constantly just in the loop and and being about no way to parallelize.
So the control glass skills like one of the first skills I built uh for cursor. Uh and glass by the way is the code name for agent window that we use internally, but it's just cursor, I guess.
Um and so this skill uh is I guess the the the code itself is not super interesting. Your agent can very easily make one for you. Uh where if if you're building an electron app or a web app or even iOS uh applications, uh you can teach your agent how to use like the Chrome dev tools protocol or through uh Apple has some utilities as well for running the simulator and taking traces and controlling programmatic control
as well. Uh so that's really useful.
Uh but one thing I want really want to talk about is uh the
this thing.
Uh has to read me.
Uh so this skill comes with this very unique feature called, oh not feature, uh unique file called the feature map.
And so the story then is like I built this skill and so now the agent was able to uh actually run the agent window and take traces and whatnot.
Uh, but it had no idea what what the agent window was.
So, um, you know, like someone say like, oh, the the left side bar is like laggy or something like that.
Or, you know, the right side the the PR tab is not working and the agent would just be like kind of flailing around.
It would spend a lot of time trying to like look up the code and, you know, where is this feature? How do I actually get to it on the UI?
which made it basically completely useless.
Uh, you know, like we would I would run this skill locally and, you know, it would spawn a dev build.
Uh, but then it just be churning like it just try to click here.
it wouldn't know how to get to things.
Um, and it was just an awful experience.
Uh, so I was putting arrows on my screen.
Um, so, uh, yeah, this this feature map has been really useful.
uh because it teaches the agent how to get to all of the features that you have. Um and in P stack, the plugin that I I've made, uh if you search for P stack cursor on Google, you'll you'll find it.
Uh but there is a create verification skill in that plugin where it actually helps you set up something like this for yourself.
Um including the feature map, so it will actually explore the code and build up this initial feature map that tells your agent how to get to all of the different features that you have.
Uh and this is extremely powerful because now that you have these user reports that come in, uh you can actually map even like a vague report or even a screenshot.
So we have this uh internally at cursor where uh we have a slack channel with, you know, lots of people giving us feedback on the agent's window and rockbot and whatnot.
Uh and often times the report is very bad like very low quality like someone will just put very often we get like a screenshot and then someone just says question mark question mark question mark like what is this?
And you know, like without this your agent like I have no clue, right? But with a feature map like this, it has a lot more context and understanding of how to actually navigate, how to get to all the different features.
Uh, so like, you know, an example like I guess like the sidebar, like what is the sidebar? Uh, you know, like all the different sub features that are present in it.
Um, like from the user point of view, here's where how to how to get to it, all the different keyboard shortcuts.
Uh even like the the what do you call it? The DOM elements or yeah, like the attributes that you use for selecting things through the CDP, uh are all there.
So, uh again, yeah, this is like really, really powerful uh for for agents.
And P stack ships uh that create verification skill, but also a maintain verification skill, uh so you can keep this up to date.
Cool. Yeah, I was just going to ask how you created that. So you might sharing a little bit more about um that that process in the context of P stack and maybe just what P stack is for the folks who are not familiar.
literally, you know, trying to climb this ladder.
I was like super into loop and I was basically nit-picking my agents to an extreme degree.
I was like I would tell it
you know, this feature has stopped working. Here's a bug report.
Like, why isn't it working?
And very often the agent will just like confidently state like, oh, it has to be this, right? It has to be this thing.
And I noticed like when I look at the actual tool calls, I noticed it wasn't actually reading the code
that I thought should be effected.
And that made me just extremely suspicious.
And at that point I was like, I'm not going to I can't trust any this agent anymore
And I think I think it's very easy to just you know like build up that distrust and not and kind of feel helpless like you know you don't know how to help your agent succeed.
But like again I think the the the management analogy is super helpful because like imagine if you were a manager of an engineering team and you had an engineer on your team who was a really good coder, no business context whatsoever you know they they just you just hired them and they they onboarded, you know like five seconds ago. Uh and so how do you actually teach that person to be effective?
So how you do that is through a skill. Uh a skill being just you know just markdown,
right? But you know encodes a lot of information instructions, a lot of
uh you can really draw out a lot of
intelligence from an agent by well some people on Twitter call it like you know pull the agent to a different latent space,
which is kind of like a fancy way of just saying, like since you know LLMs are sort of like
they predict the next token,
uh when you give it some high quality tokens to begin with, then you know it it can kind of pattern match
on like a higher space that's you know smarter.
Um so that's like a very interesting
model there. But yeah, I built Pstack very very incrementally.
Uh so uh started with just really observing how agents, you know all the different failure modes of of that agents were having. And every time I saw that I just, okay I'm just going to make that a skill,
right? Like stop hallucinating, actually go and search up look up the code, use a lot of sub agents.
Uh and yeah, stop guessing.
Yeah, that makes sense.
One one kind of follow question here, both for myself and for people on the chat.
So, I guess it's two two parts.
So one is like how do you maintain these skills? So like the product changes over time.
Obviously there's a lot of people who are shipping against the code base.
So how do these skills get maintained?
Uh and then second to that is like, how do you know when your verification is is good enough?
Uh like and you know, you can trust that the verification loops that you've built are going to I guess you trust the outputs when when they're done.
Uh yeah, maybe I'll talk about um I think I'm somewhat related. Maybe I'll start with this one first.
So like how do I maintain these skills?
So um if you're not familiar with this concept, an is essentially like a way to uh the mental model I have is like it's like a unit test for an agent.
Um and uh you can actually make your own. You don't need like a special framework for them.
You can build you can build one depending on like you know how scientific and how vigorous you want to be.
Uh my screen is red.
Yeah, there's a little button um sorry, like disabling the drawing or something. I can't see my screen.
Yeah, sorry. If you guys could not draw on the screen that would be great.
But there's a little button in the control. Yeah, the the little drop down.
Um clear.
Yeah. Okay, yeah. You got it. Perfect.
Continue.
Yeah, so are a way to unit test your skills basically.
And actually in Pstack we ship under we have a playbook, if you search for it it's called playbook. Um and it's uh
uh it's like not it's actually pretty pretty rigorous the way it's done.
Uh, but um essentially what I do is I spawn a lot of different sub agents.
I have like my main coordinator agent uh come up with a rubric for uh what I want the skill to do.
Um and then it spawns all these sub agents and it it creates individual directories for them uh which are cleverly named to not let the sub agent know that it's being evaluated.
Because uh agents can actually tell and when they do they change their behavior.
Uh, but it does a bunch of stuff like that to um essentially, yeah, like test whether or not the skill I'm making or changing is actually doing what I think it does.
Um and one of the really nice things about cursor is that we are we we support so many different models.
So you can actually evaluate your skill across all sorts of different models um and you know, get a sense of how well it performs across
that different matrix, um especially for the models that you use.
Uh, so I use this a lot. Every time I I modify a skill, I will run one of these uh like the playbook uh and make sure that, you know, it's actually
Uh, but I will say like maintaining skills is actually pretty hard. Uh, it requires I think a lot of taste and observation.
So you kind of need to be very good at being a backseat driver, you know what I mean? Like, if you do, if you've ever done pair programming for example,
uh and you watch a co-worker code and you're just like, you could probably do this better, you know, you can do it like, why did you not do this, right?
You ask a lot of questions to your co-worker and it's kind of a similar thing here, you like, you don't want to just be a passive observer of the agent, you want to be very
Uh, you know, obviously you can use something like Pstack, but if you're building your own set of skills, it's very
The model is not being biased.
Right? The model that's judging all of the sub agents that are running the thing. Uh but you can also like Hill climb.
So, meaning that you can you can use like slash loop in cursor.
And you can say, okay, keep looping on this eval, right? Until everything is 10 out of 10 as an example.
Uh and I did the same the basically the same approach with the control scale. And so, I kind of it was very it was very hands off actually.
Uh so, you know, I uh I kind of built I built that skill that way, like the CLI and that skill. Um and over time is gotten really good.
Uh but yeah, it was definitely not super smooth at the beginning, it required a lot of iteration and I think there's a analogy here, which is um
well, I make this analogy later in a different slide on my drawing here. Uh but I think of it like
uh you know, as a as a engineer now, you're sort of more like uh like maybe a manager or the analogy I like is like you're like a a chef in a restaurant.
Uh you're you're the head chef.
Uh you're not cooking all the food yourself anymore.
You have a team of cooks, right? You have line cooks, you have a soup chef, you have all these different stations.
Um and it's your job to really design the environment. You know, you you you're in charge of setting up the kitchen, you're in charge of, you know, like giving tasks to different people.
So, um
yeah, it's a very interesting way of working.
Uh but yeah, that's that's how I basically built uh these verification skills.
Yeah, just just one thought there and like I want to go try to go one layer deeper.
So, are you let's say we want to build um an eval or a skill for for something and we wanted to kind of get better on its own, which is what I think you're suggesting.
Uh are you doing that in like a work tree, kind of isolated with like the sub agents and then the reviewer agent and and all that? Is it happening like in some type of cloud hosted environment?
Like what's the the more the practical steps if I want to go do this uh and like set up a verification system for something?
What would I what would I do or where would I start?
Um I think that uh the best place to start is local because you can observe.
You can definitely observe what your agents are doing.
So, uh if you're building a verification field for yourself, uh I would definitely start local and just have your agent bring up the application.
whether it's like a CLI or uh desktop app or whatever.
And so you can actually observe right, you can see how the agent is interacting with the the application.
You can see it, you know, how it calls like the different APIs that that allow it to interact with the uh the application.
Um but uh for me personally, uh I have basically been kind of all in, mostly all in on cloud agents because they're extremely powerful.
Uh and the really powerful thing about cursor is the the cloud agents actually, where if you spend a little bit of time setting up your environment,
these control skills, these verification skills pay a huge amount of dividend.
Because it's not just something that makes you as a single engineer better, it actually levels up your whole team, uh and even your whole company because uh you can actually start thinking about
cloud agents, you start thinking about automations that automatically do things, like uh oh I I get I kind of talk about this a bit later, but I'll just kind of
get into it, uh where where, you know, for example like I talk a lot about this agent we have called Benny, right, who who uh, you know, takes all of the bug reports that we get,
and it automatically goes off in the cloud, opens up a cloud uh it's, you know, its desktop.
It runs cursor in its own computer, and it uses the same control skills
to interact with the application and try to reproduce the bug uh or the user report.
Right? And this is so so powerful because at once I can immediately I I get so much
information from this automatically.
Like here in this example you can see that uh the Benny actually reproduced the bug, uh but it's already fixed online.
So it actually confirms that we fixed this problem already, and all I need to do is just release another build of of cursor. Uh so there's like huge information
there that I didn't have to go off and sit with an agent, you know, and spend an hour trying to figure like is this fixed, is this not fixed?
So you you you gain back so much time, uh but you know, everybody on my team benefits from this.
Everybody in the company benefits from this.
Uh, so definitely think that uh, you know, keeping these using cloud agents is super powerful.
Uh but yeah, it's like a journey. You have to trust it first, right before you you get to this point.
And that's it goes back to what I was saying here where, you know, it's very hard, it's it's almost impossible and I was definitely encourage you not to try to jump from, you know, like if you're still in this zone,
you don't want to jump to like I'm going to spawn a 100 or a thousand of cloud agents right now because you're just going to waste a lot of tokens, um and it's going to be extremely expensive.
Yeah, so just to kind of recap so far, basically the if we want to go on the journey that you've kind of gone on, it would be just start with verification, um building some some skills and some some ways of determining that the agents are producing.
At least like correct code whether like you said whether it's good code or not, that's a separate question, but like it's it's technically solving the problem by looking at, you know, stack traces, looking at, you know, the the actual behavior in the app and so on.
Um and then once we trust it locally, then we can start to think about scaling into the cloud and running more agents that are
picking up signals, I guess on their own, right? So whether that's like a bug report that comes in or something that they can go and pick it up and solve the problem and and give us back a PR.
you know take a look at pizza and kind of fork it,
make it your own, improve the skills, definitely encourage that.
Uh but for me, I really all about it just keeps coming back to trust.
You know, every one of us here in this chat have a different standard for engineering.
Uh and there are different things that are important for us in our code base.
And uh when you are able to encode all of that into skills and you can verify that your agents actually doing them, that allows you to really kind of ascend this curve.
Uh there's another piece I want to to talk about um if there's Yeah, go for it.
I'll I'll take a few more questions as they go, but
Yeah, I think there's a third part to this, which I haven't talked about yet, which is kind of an interesting one, which is like refactoring and rewriting, like one of the uh I guess most controversial, one of the most controversial topics in the industry, I think, is like, should you rewrite your app or not?
Um, because I think engineers are very prone to this where especially when you join a company, you come in and you see like the code base and you're like, oh man, this is shit. Like who wrote this code?
You know, it's terrible. I want to rewrite the whole thing.
There is a very common inclination and I think a lot of, you know, before agents, um and I guess arguably even now, people will definitely discourage you from rewriting stuff.
But I'm actually here to make the case for why you might want to consider it.
Um because I think it really depends.
Uh you know, uh Greenfield applications I think are actually in a pretty good spot, especially if they're set up well already.
Uh and like recently I've been talking to some people, but uh you know, I was just observing, I I just noticed this
parallel, which is that a lot of big tech company problems are now everybody's problems. Um and the big tech company problem, you know, like when I was working at meta, like we had this giant mono repo.
We had like, I don't know, tens of thousands of engineers just, you know, like banging on their keyboards and chipping code.
And a lot of really great engineers at meta,
uh, but uh I would say like, you know, you'll be surprised that the code quality is actually not that good. Um, and so I often joke that like, you know, before AI sloth, we had human sloth.
Um, and so you know, I think a lot of big tech infra, like uh like what meta has or Google, you know, you really big tech companies are actually designed for that, where you you're sort of like, you're catering to the the, you know, like
it sounds it sounds a bad to say, but like the the least capable engineer on your team,
right? You build you build frameworks, you build conventions, you build guard rails, you know, you restrict credentials so that, you know, your intern doesn't wipe your production database.
Um, there's uh, you know, if you have that level of infra already, I think your agents can actually already do a very solid job, right? Because they have the the guard rails are already in place for
agents to not cause havoc or not cause too much havoc uh in your code base. Um and you can always add more, you know, guard rails.
Uh, but I think like Greenfield applications, especially are, you know, like the brand new applications are like the biggest risk in my opinion, uh and also the greatest opportunity.
Because, you know, if you vibe code a project, uh a prototype, um like we did for Grot, you know, Grot was spun up very, very very quickly.
Um and if you if you haven't heard of of Grot, it's like a a new application we just launched yesterday. Uh, it's it's really cool.
Uh, lets you orchestrate your create like individual agents that have their own identity and you can kind of orchestrate them.
It's super cool, definitely check it out.
Uh but yeah, that was like a very it was a very green field application, like most prototypes are. So it's like vibe coded very quickly.
Humans were not reading the code at all.
And uh I had this tweet recently uh where I said something about organic architecture.
Um, let me find it.
Uh, but the idea is that uh when you have a completely live coded application, you essentially have no guard rails whatsoever.
So uh your agents when you give them a task, they will just solve it in whatever method is the most convenient.
And over time you get into this uh situation where you have a code base that is spiraling out of control because you don't understand it.
Uh, your agents understand it, I guess, in a way, but like they've built something that is
you know, optimized for short for shortcuts, uh and uh, you know, it will you will suffer you'll have a lot of issues with that application.
Uh, so I think starting your code base with uh like very strong constraints is
very much needed, uh, because like when you have a code base that you can trust, right? When you have guard rails that actually help you uh uh help your agents, right? Good code.
You can get into the, you know, like into this part of the curve where I I where like I I said, you know, I woke up today and I had like 20 PRs merged
uh by my agents. And that's because I invested a lot
of time, uh over 600 PRs.
I I I calculated yesterday.
Uh when I refactored all of Grot to this new architecture that I've been building.
Um, and yeah, I've got to a point where I
I don't really look I really don't look at the code anymore.
And um, I say that not just, you know, to sell you tokens, but because I, you know, it it took a lot of work to get to that point.
I spent a lot of tokens to get
the code base to this point where I no longer have to look at it.
Uh, but I'm very excited because
and what generally the size
of PR is um if it's only a couple lines of code or
you know, um yeah.
Um
I think it depends uh me trying to do this in a way where I'm not going to like
You yeah, you don't have to share the actual number of like the actual
just just just fine.
benchmark, but like we have
so okay, this is not
that interesting, but
uh, well, fun fact, is that virtualization in Gbot and in uh cursor is actually powered by uh pretex, uh which is a help new library that someone's built, um that's really interesting. You should you should check it out.
But that's not really that important.
Uh, I think the average PR size I actually don't know. I I don't know if I want to click on these.
Uh I probably can, but I would say like they can range anywhere from a few hundred lines or 50 lines to like 1,000 depending on what the thing is doing.
Uh so like here I'm I'm really deleting a bunch of files so I expect that it's just like mostly deletion. Uh but yeah it it kind of varies.
There's only hard
hard cap. They're all like 50 line
Definitely no hard
cap, but I I do encourage my agents to split up their work into multiple PRs.
Uh I do that mostly because uh
I like I like the idea of I guess maybe this is much harder to do now as in the world of agents and you have like so many commits.
But I like the idea that you know the Git history is a very rich source of context, uh, and I like the I like each PR to sort of atomically describe what that
small piece of thing is doing, which also makes it easier for me to revert changes and like figure out
you know, oh I shipped that about again, it's this it's here, it's not in this 40,000 line PR where you know who knows what landed in there.
Uh, but yeah I don't have a hard cap on PR size.
Cool. And then um yeah, also quick question on like CI. So again you don't have to go into like the screen share like your CI does, but just generally, would you describe what the CI kind of looks like or how strict it is?
Uh, yeah, so uh well specifically for rockbot, so dune is the is the sort of cheeky code code name for the architecture that we've built for rockbot. Um the CI looks pretty annoying because there's checks for everything. So like literally I have uh uh well if you've written any React for example, you know, you know that one of the biggest foot guns in React is use effect. Uh so in uh dune and in rockbot we've banned use effect.
So dune is the the mental model of what Dune is, uh you can kind of think of it as like next JS for uh electron apps and it's designed for agents to write, uh and it's like custom for you know our agent for our applications. Um so the CI checks are very like specific to that like you know, don't use use effect. It's it's it's banned like CI will fail uh and yell at you.
We have like some of the more interesting ones that people might raise eyebrows is like I actually banned code comments as well, uh which is very interesting. Uh, but I've noticed that 99% of the time agents just write code comments that
kind of describe some historical thing that is actually totally irrelevant to the code.
Um like it will often say like you know, oh Lawrence said you should never do this and it's now in the in a code comment. Like what? Like why?
That was I didn't say that as like a durable, you know, global rule. I just meant like your this PR sucks and you should change that part.
But agents don't really understand us that well surprisingly, uh and or they kind of assume too much and they kind of do things in like very stupid ways.
you know, especially when it doesn't have this architecture yet.
I plan to do bring this learning back there
and kind of refactor everything there.
Uh, but, uh, it just regresses super often.
Uh, because, uh, there's, just one example is like we have very poor
isolation between processes.
So, like on you know, on on electron you have a renderer thread that renders your UI, but you also have like a main thread that you can run other code
that you know, doesn't need to block the renderer.
Um, but we do a poor job of separating those things, and so often times you just accidentally
have code that gets pulled into running on the renderer thread, right? And then all of a sudden you're competing with
the the renderer that, you know, that has a very, if you want like 60 FPS, you have to every frame that gets drawn has to be done in 16 milliseconds.
So very, very small, you know, deadline for frame.
Uh, if you want, you know, a very smooth product.
Uh, and when you start building, bringing in accidentally bringing in, you know, things that are like very computationally heavy or they have a lot of IO.
you know losing frames get long tasks
that take more than 16 millisecond and you just get this really choppy experience.
So all of those patterns that we've learned basically building Electron apps, we've encoded into this framework, and it becomes like a hard failure.
So I literally in in, we literally have a directory called electron main, electron renderer, and we have uh import uh CI, I guess where we actually check the dependency graph to make sure they're not accidentally importing
code from one directory to another. Uh, so that's enforced
by CI. Um as well as bugbot, uh which is our which cursors um like code review tool that runs on CI. Uh, you know, in our agents MB, it's everywhere like so I I I I um
I have this thing here where I I talk about like um you know like there are multiple layers I think for building a good code base.
Uh obviously the code base is one where uh if you have an architecture like this, where it's extremely strict, uh you know, the the
the way to build features is very conventional. That's like the strongest, strongest level of enforcement because agents just love to copy existing patterns. So, uh one example of this in is like we have this these concepts called like a feature and we have entry points and transcript cards, like you know the cards that you see in the chat, these are all like like nouns I guess in in the framework and so there's a very conventional way of creating them. And so like a feature is all in a single directory as an example. And so all of the code that contributes to that feature lives in one directory. So it's all collocated in one place. Makes it super easy, you know, agents don't have to like uh group around and try to figure out like where all the things are.
It just looks like a feature and like, oh, okay, I'm working on the onboarding feature in. Uh I'm just going to work in this directory and
for 80% of the work is mostly just very encapsulated there. But uh like
it's like very it's like designed again for you know like the dumbest agent, like you don't have to think, right? The the the the one of the key principles I have for this framework is like
the shortest the shortest path is the best path.
So uh because that plays exactly to how agents love to write, we like to take shortcuts really. You know, they'll find the quickest way to
solve the problem. So why not make that the best way to solve the problem?
Uh so I I I probably won't get into all the specific details. Um and uh the this framework is really more of a collection of ideas and principles rather than something that will open source.
Uh you can you can you know screenshot this I guess if you want and uh tell your agent to uh do some build build something like this for you too.
Um yeah, but it's really all about the layers. Uh you know, like the the code base is one part with features uh and directories and you know, import uh blocking import dependencies uh that shouldn't be imported.
Uh but and and all enforces that and static analysis.
So like uh there's CI checks, we have a lot of linnts for bad patterns that we observe. Uh compiler diagnostics.
Uh there's also rules in bugbot which are um I think like three, four, five are more soft, right?
These two actually make make CI rid, right? So you know, there's a hard constraint where the agent can just write crappy code.
For rules and skills and bugbot, your agents can still forget, right? You can still or it may not always consistently apply them.
So I like to layer them, but I don't I don't like to rely on them as the only source of enforcement.
Because it's very very soft, right? And if you if you only have rules and bugbot and skills and a style guide for your code, you will
it's only a matter of time before your code base looks like complete trash. I'm sorry to say that, but uh I definitely recommend you know, like you know, investing
in, you know, things that can be hard enforced, right? And this is why, you know, maybe uh the choice of text stack that you use is also very important.
Um, like I think for example Rust is sort of sneaking, you know it's like getting super popular again, uh because the compiler is so strict, right?
you know, we're eating the code anyway.
Okay, you should not do this.
Every time you have to do that, you should consider that as a code smell, like a anti pattern.
And you should say, okay, instead of me commenting on the PR,
how do I turn this into a hard rule, right?
How do I turn this into a lint rule?
How do I turn this into a CI failure?
Or how do I even categorically eliminate this problem
uh entirely?
Uh I I can talk about another migration I've done, but I'll probably pause here. Sure.
Yeah, I feel like that's that's where I am, to be honest, is is what you're describing right now, which is like I don't have all of these rules.
Uh so I have some things to go do after this session uh in terms of being able to scale my agents.
I'm I'm definitely on like the uh you know
maybe a couple of parallel ones locally.
Stage like two to three locally.
And I'm sure most people here are on the same, so uh
yeah, I know we only have a couple of minutes left.
Lauren, is there anything else that you wanted to to highlight? I obviously there's lots of questions.
I can grab more, but I want to give you a few minutes if there's any else you want to talk.
Well, I think I've been yapping for kind of a lot, so maybe let's just do questions.
Okay, cool.
Uh one question that had uh a couple of uh came up a couple of times was just around like token usage.
So the the question is like is is what you're describing a realistic thing for people who are on, you know, uh a normal set of token usage they don't have, you know, obviously unlimited tokens uh to work with.
Oh, I think that's a really good point.
I mean, like obviously, you know, I work at a AI lab where we have unlimited tokens.
So, uh, I definitely cannot say that, you know, this is something everyone should do in the exact same way that I did it.
I think it's possible to get to this point without, you know, breaking the bank.
But you know, if you are like an engineering leader or, you know, you're you're you have a startup that you lead,
um, I think the main is a question of ROI.
Um and it's like uh yes, you spend a lot of money on tokens in the upfront stage.
You know, like refactoring a code base is going to take a lot of tokens.
Uh adding all these things uh is going to take a bunch of tokens.
But if we're hitting to a world where agents are writing all the code and, you know, you want to be very lean, right?
You don't want to have to hire, you don't want to be you don't want to become like meta, right?
I mean like in terms of you don't want to become a 10,000 person engineering org because
I mean that's a cool problem to have, but also, you know, you have so much overhead.
There's like planning, you know, like it's it's a personally I I wouldn't
uh
it's not super fun.
But um, I think you want to stay very nimble, right? And you want to you want to be like agents are all about
allowing you to do things that you couldn't do before.
That's really to me like the value of agents.
You know, it's not just storing tokens on every single little thing.
But um, to me like the thing I couldn't do before is like enforce this level of constraints in a code base by myself, right?
Like I'm just a single person, you know, uh it would have taken me years to build this framework uh and do all the refactoring,
and test everything myself and verify, you know, like run imagine if there it was just me, right?
No in in pre agent era, just like running, you know, by it would take me so long, right?
And my salary is pretty high, right?
Like, so, you know,
the the question I think an engineering leader might have is just then, you know, like what is there's a trade-off of
do you hire someone to do this? Or do you spend the tokens to set up a code base?
So that even the the most naive, right?
The dumbest agents can do a good job.
And when you actually get to this point, like even agents that are not, you know, fable size, do an excellent job over writing code.
And this pays a lot of dividends as well for me personally where I've empowered
not just myself, but again, like PMs, designers, engineers who are not familiar with to just contribute in a way that is sustainable.
So I think yeah, it's definitely like a trade-off for sure.
You know, like nothing is like free for sure, and tokens are pretty expensive.
Uh, but oh, actually,
uh, I I don't know how many of you have seen this, but we actually announced Grock 4.6 today.
So very exciting.
Finally out.
Um, so yeah, Grock 4.6 would be like a great. There's very, very smart.
Uh, it's really good on the on the benchmarks.
Uh, and it's the same the tokens uh, well, I hopefully I'm not saying this incorrectly, but
uh, I believe the cost for token is the same as 4.5.
So you're actually getting more intelligence for the same cost.
Uh, I think this is an area that tries to in space AI try to really optimize for.
Like that Pareto frontier of, you know, cost versus intelligence.
Uh, you know, we don't necessarily want to build the biggest model ever because that is extremely expensive to run.
It's really about like how do you find that sweet spot, right?
Uh, but uh, yeah, I think to kind of round it up,
um, I think it's like a it's it's there's a if you do your own analysis, I feel like it's pretty positive.
It'll be pretty positive that the ROI you get from investing in stuff like this, uh, just empowers not just yourself, but your whole team to be so much more productive.
Right? Like imagine if you have an army of engineers like me who are shipping so much improvements and and bug fixes, uh, you know, every day,
right? Like that is pretty exciting.
Cool. One one last question before we wrap up.
This one is for the people in product on on the call.
So let's say we do have an engine engineers who are shipping like Lauren.
I'm just curious like, how is the product team or other functions of your company keeping
very familiar interface. It looks like I message.
um and it's very fun to you know, you can give your agen
a fun name.
Uh you can have you can kind of do orchestration with in a very like natural way where you can sort of you know each agent like a person and now you got a team of agents like working on you have one one agent per account that you manage as an example. Or if you're a PM you have
you know, you can have an agent that summarizes all the work that Lauren did last night and then now you know what I did, right?
So I think our PMs are leveraging that a lot and they're shipping code too.
Uh so, you know, like oftentimes they will just say, oh, here's a bug, I fixed it. Can you look at it? And then I'll go review it and actually it's just perfect. I'm like okay, stamp.
Uh so uh that I think that shows that you know, the the Dune architecture is holding up, right? The all the the really strict constraints allow
people who are not experts in engineering to contribute at a high level. Uh so I I feel like I'm already seeing that pay off a lot where
Um and we have a lot planned, so I'm very excited uh to, you know, uh to to ship more ship more stuff.
Shama stuff.